Mark Johnson

markwj.co.uk linkedin.com/in/markwj mark@markwj.co.uk +447856 892672

Personal statement 2

I am a young and ambitious Computer Science student that has a keen interest in all kinds of technology and the opportunities that it can bring. I am focused on creating an exciting career for myself, which I have demonstrated by gaining developer experience in a start-up company during the summer of my first year at university. I enjoy challenging myself in all aspects of my life and I have an interest for working in innovative companies that embrace technology.

Education

2013-Present BSc (Hons) Computer Science with Placement Year, University of Bath

First Year: First (79.7%) (Awarded Netcraft Prize for outstanding performance)

•	Computer Systems Architecture I	85%	•	Computer Systems Architecture II	78%
•	Discrete Mathematics	86%	•	Analytical Mathematics	88%
•	Principles of Programming I	78%	•	Principles of Programing II	84%
•	Software Engineering	70%			

Second Year: Modules to be studied

Designing Interactive Systems, Software Systems Development, Advanced Programming Principles, Foundations of Computation I, Foundations of Computer Graphics, Fundamentals of Pattern Analysis.

2006-2013 Hardenhuish Secondary School & Sixth Form

- A Levels: A*AA in Mathematics, Business & Computing. (380 UCAS points)
- AS Levels: ABB in Further Mathematics, Critical Thinking & Physics.
- **GCSE:** 6A*'s, 5A's, 1B.

Other qualifications and achievements

After being highly motivated at a careers talk from EarSoft, I approached their founder and taught myself C during exams to secure a 12-week summer job in a development role at their start-up. My development is used to support their patented product of Level. This experience early on in my career has given me a firm focus for working with agile companies who are at the forefront of technology.

During my first year of studies I was nominated as an Academic Representative for my course, which required clear communication skills to accurately represent student's feedback and affect change within the department. Tour guiding as a Student Ambassador for the Computer Science department involved working as part of a team to show prospective students around the campus and answer any questions in a friendly and professional manner. I was awarded a Netcraft Computer Science Prize for my outstanding first year results.

Skills

Development in C and C++ with EarSoft, using git. At university I have learnt Python and Java and achieved a first in each of these programming modules which involved networking, threading, gui's and Al. I also have previous experience in Visual Basic, developing a program for the visualisation of Vector questions for the Sixth Form Maths department in my A Level computing project.

Work experience

June 2014 - September 2014 Junior Developer, EarSoft.

I developed an audio analysis software library based in C and created example client C++ applications demonstrating API usage. This library is used by EarSoft to collect statistics on audio files and helps with development of their internationally patented product, Level. I have experienced a range of business areas, such as UX design for the chrome extension.

January 2011 – June 2014 IT Consultant, THJ Engineering Services Ltd.

I have supported the growth of THJ Engineering Services, purchasing computer systems, installing and maintaining software packages and designing business cards.

October 2013 - March 2014 Student Ambassador, University of Bath

I worked as a tour guide on the Computer Science UCAS days. During these weekly events I lead tours for prospective students, and I improved both my communication and interpersonal skills while acting as an ambassador for the University of Bath.

October 2013 - January 2014 Sales Advisor, Debenhams

By showing ambition and working in multiple departments, I increased our flexibility as a team to meet targets. Working whilst studying improved my time management skills.

July 2011 - October 2012 Waiter, The Rowden Arms

Working as a waiter greatly helped my communication and delegation skills. A fast moving environment developed my time management skills to handle time pressures professionally.

Voluntary work

September 2014 - Present Peer Mentor, University of Bath

Responsible for mentoring a small group of first year students through their first year at Bath, encouraging mentees to become involved in campus life and develop support networks.

September 2013 - May 2014 Undergraduate Academic Representative, University of Bath

Gathered student's feedback and represented their opinions accurately at committees as part of the department's decision making process. Achieved an increase in the amount of timetabled post-grad support provided to first year students in programming modules.

July 2011 – July 2011 Apple Computers (Farpoint Developments Ltd.)

Working in a high end retail environment I achieved product sales from actively listening to customers, identifying their needs and delivering effective solutions to their problems.

Activities and interests

I have a passion for sport and fitness. I am a keen runner, having completed a half marathon in a sub 1:40 time; I also train regularly in the gym and play competitive club level football. I enjoy playing both acoustic and electric guitar and I also have experience with piano and drums.

References

Steve Baldwin
Founder/CEO
EarSoft
Campus North, Sunco House, 5 Carliol Square
Newcastle Upon Tyne
NE1 6UF
steve.baldwin@earsoft.co.uk
07950 098033

Dr Julian Padget
Personal Tutor
Department of Computer Science
University of Bath
Bath
BA2 7AY
j.a.padget@bath.ac.uk
01225 386971